Andy Brummitt

Web Developer

21 Homefield Drive Braintree CM7 2DF 07562 010888 andybrummitt93@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://andy-brummitt.co.uk/ **Github:** https://github.com/Andybrummitt

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andy-brummitt-dev/

SKILLS

Javascript | React | CSS | SCSS | HTML | Node | Express | Firebase | Git

WEB DEVELOPMENT

I have two years experience in creating websites and an in-depth understanding of front-end development with Javascript and React.

My portfolio is the best representation of my work.

Portfolio Link: https://andy-brummitt.co.uk/

Some Personal Projects

Mixin https://mixinapp.herokuapp.com/

Mixin is a cocktail recipe web app that utilises the cocktailDB REST API to offer the user a seamless experience searching for cocktails that they can make.

Chatty https://chattyapplication.netlify.app/

This app is a serverless chat app similar to facebook messenger. The user can authenticate with google or sign up with their own email and password and can search for users by username to chat to. To test this application you can use any login details as long as the email format is accepted. I've created a

couple of users that you can search for to use the application (the usernames are test1 and test2).

Battleship Game https://battleshipjsgame.herokuapp.com/

This project is essentially a web based version of the popular board game, Battleship, with a graphical user interface. Users can battle against a bot that has been programmed to guess random tiles until it hits a ship tile, in which case it will guess tiles around the ship tile.

Summary

Despite not having any formal experience yet, I believe I have the passion and discipline to make it in this industry, having built apps and sites from my own intuition for the past two years. I am fully dedicated to this career and I feel that's reflective of my portfolio.

EDUCATION

Writtle University College - BSc Hons: Sports & Exercise Performance 2014 - 2017 Grade: 2:2 (59%)

Chelmsford College - Diploma Media Studies

2009 - 2011 Grade: Merit

EXPERIENCE

Order Fulfilment, Customer Support - *Xylem Holdings (table-tennis-tables.co.uk)*

May 2013 - PRESENT

Working in a relatively small company, I have had many roles during my time here. I started out picking and packing orders and handling dispatch but soon moved on to manage a small group of employees in the department.

As I was interested in web development, I am often asked to consult with my employer to make small changes on the e-commerce website using my HTML and CSS knowledge, though this is not my primary role.

Throughout my time I have regularly provided customer support which has given me lots of experience in dealing with a range of customer service inquiries.

Professional Ice Hockey Player - Hull Stingrays

August 2011 - December 2012

After completing college I signed a professional contract with Hull Stingrays, an Elite League team. This was a dream of mine growing up, having played since the age of four. I played for the team until December 2012 when I was injured playing for Great Britain in the World Junior Championships in Ukraine. During this time I learned to remain disciplined and focused during times of struggle and reinforced my teamwork skills learned earlier in a professional environment.